A Guide to the Papers of the President of the University of Virginia, Office Administrative Files, 1965-1966
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of the President of the University of Virginia, Office Administrative Files 1965-1966
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-2/1/2.691
This collection consists of 33,000 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Access restrictions may apply to specific student records under the terms of the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (F.E.R.P.A.).
Acquisition Information
This collection was transferred to the library on 25 July 1969.
Scope and Content Information
These files constitute the major record series generated by the president of the University of Virginia. The records consist chiefly of correspondence, but also include reports, minutes, clippings, memoranda, and related papers concerning all areas of business of the president's office.
The papers consist of: general and committee files.
Contents List
- Series I: General Files, 1965-1966
  - "A - Am" Miscellaneous 1965-1966 (Box 1)
  - "An - Az" Miscellaneous 1965-1966 (Box 1)
  - Academic Deans 1965-1966 (Box 1)
  - Academic Deans 1965-1966 (Box 1)
  - Adams Papers (see also Madison Papers, Jefferson Papers) 1965-1966 (Box 1)
  - Admissions - General 1965-1966 (Box 2)
  - Admissions - Applicants 1965-1966 (Box 2)
  - Admissions - Reports 1965-1966 (Box 2)
  - Advisory Panel on ROTC Affairs 1965-1966 (Box 2)
  - Air Force Academy - Board of Visitors 1965-1966 (Box 2)
  - Air Force and Air Force ROTC 1965-1966 (Box 3)
  - Albemarle County Public Schools (folder empty) 1965-1966 (Box 3)
  - Alumni Association - General 1965-1966 (Box 3)
  - Alumni Association - Chapters Planned (folder empty) 1965-1966 (Box 3)
  - Alumni Day 1965-1966 (Box 3)
  - Alumni Fund, University of Virginia 1965-1966 (Box 3)
  - Alumni - Medical 1965-1966 (Box 3)
  - Alumni News (folder empty) 1965-1966 (Box 3)
  - Alumni - speeches (see Speeches under "S") (folder empty) 1965-1966 (Box 3)
  - Alumni - Alumni Recognition 1965-1966 (Box 3)
  - American Association of University Professors 1965-1966 (Box 3)
  - American Council on Education 1965-1966 (Box 3)
  - American Council on Education - Bulletin on International Education; Higher Education and National Affairs; Special Report on Federal Programs 1965-1966 (Box 4)
  - Annual Reports 1965-1966 (Box 4)
  - Applications - "A" 1965-1966 (Box 4)
  - Applications - "B" 1965-1966 (Box 4)
  - Applications - "C" 1965-1966 (Box 4)
  - Applications - "D" 1965-1966 (Box 4)
  - Applications - "E" 1965-1966 (Box 4)
  - Applications - "F" 1965-1966 (Box 4)
  - Applications - "G" 1965-1966 (Box 4)
  - Applications - "H" 1965-1966 (Box 4)
  - Applications - "I" (folder empty) 1965-1966 (Box 4)
  - Applications - "J" 1965-1966 (Box 4)
  - Applications - "K" 1965-1966 (Box 4)
  - Applications - "L" 1965-1966 (Box 4)
  - Applications - "M" 1965-1966 (Box 4)
  - Applications - "N" 1965-1966 (Box 4)
  - Applications - "O" 1965-1966 (Box 4)
  - Applications - "P" 1965-1966 (Box 4)
  - Applications - "Q" 1965-1966 (Box 4)
  - Applications - "R" 1965-1966 (Box 4)
  - Applications - "S" 1965-1966 (Box 4)
  - Applications - "T" 1965-1966 (Box 4)
  - Applications - "U" (folder empty) 1965-1966 (Box 4)
  - Applications - "V" 1965-1966 (Box 4)
  - Applications - "W" 1965-1966 (Box 4)
  - Applications - "X - Y - Z" 1965-1966 (Box 4)
  - Architecture - General 1965-1966 (Box 4)
  - Architecture - Museum of Fine Arts (folder empty) 1965-1966 (Box 4)
  - Architecture - Personnel 1965-1966 (Box 4)
  - Army - General (folder empty) 1965-1966 (Box 4)
  - Army - ROTC 1965-1966 (Box 4)
  - Army - Judge Advocate General's (J. A. G.) School 1965-1966 (Box 4)
  - Army - Judge Advocate General's (J. A. G.) School Building (folder empty) 1965-1966 (Box 4)
  - Art 1965-1966 (Box 5)
  - Art Commission 1965-1966 (Box 5)
  - Asian Studies Consortium 1965-1966 (Box 5)
  - Association of American Colleges 1965-1966 (Box 5)
  - Association of American Universities 1965-1966 (Box 5)
  - Association of Virginia Colleges 1965-1966 (Box 5)
  - Astronomy 1965-1966 (Box 5)
  - Athletics - ACC 1965-1966 (Box 5)
  - Athletics - General 1965-1966 (Box 5)
  - Athletics - Grants-in-Aid Program 1965-1966 (Box 6)
  - Athletics - Finances 1965-1966 (Box 6)
  - Athletics - Football Letters 1965-1966 (Box 6)
  - Athletics - NCAA 1965-1966 (Box 6)
  - Athletics - Football: Duke, 18 September 1965 1965-1966 (Box 6)
  - Athletics - Football: Clemson, 25 September 1965 1965-1966 (Box 6)
  - Athletics - Football: V. M. I., 9 October 1965 1965-1966 (Box 6)
  - Athletics - Football: N. C. State, Homecoming, Commonwealth Day, Band - 30 October 1965 1965-1966 (Box 6)
  - Athletics - Football: South Carolina, 6 November 1965 1965-1966 (Box 6)
  - Athletics - 3 -2 - 2 Committee 1965-1966 (Box 6)
  - Athletics - Personnel 1965-1966 (Box 6)
  - Atlantic Council of the U. S. 1965-1966 (Box 6)
  - Atomic Energy Commission 1965-1966 (Box 6)
  - Audit Reports 1965-1966 (Box 6)
  - "Ba - Bd" Miscellaneous 1965-1966 (Box 6)
  - "Be - Bo" Miscellaneous 1965-1966 (Box 6)
  - "Bp - Bz" Miscellaneous 1965-1966 (Box 7)
  - Berkeley, Francis L., Jr. 1965-1966 (Box 7)
  - Biology - Blandy Farm 1965-1966 (Box 7)
  - Biology - General 1965-1966 (Box 7)
  - Biology - Mountain Lake 1965-1966 (Box 7)
  - Biophysics 1965-1966 (Box 7)
  - Budget - Budget Requests 1965-1966 (Box 7)
  - Budget Office - Capital Outlay 1965-1966 (Box 8)
  - Budget Office - Director's Office 1965-1966 (Box 8)
  - Budget Office - Miscellaneous Information 1965-1966 (Box 8)
  - Budget Office - Operating 1965-1966 (Box 8)
  - Buildings and Grounds - General 1965-1966 (Box 8)
  - Buildings and Grounds - Progress Reports 1965-1966 (Box 8)
  - Bursar (includes information on tuition, fees, employee benefits, etc.) 1965-1966 (Box 8)
  - Bureau of Population and Economic Research 1965-1966 (Box 8)
  - "Ca - Ck" Miscellaneous 1965-1966 (Box 8)
  - "Cl - Cz" Miscellaneous 1965-1966 (Box 9)
  - Calendar of Events 1965-1966 (Box 9)
  - Catholic Center 1965-1966 (Box 9)
  - Cavalier Daily 1965-1966 (Box 9)
  - Center for Advanced Studies in the Sciences 1965-1966 (Box 9)
  - Center for Urban Studies 1965-1966 (Box 9)
  - Chemistry - General 1965-1966 (Box 9)
  - Chemistry - Chemistry Building 1965-1966 (Box 9)
  - Children's Rehabilitation Center (see also Rehabilitation Center) 1965-1966 (Box 10)
  - Civic Beautification (folder empty) 1965-1966 (Box 10)
  - Civil Defense 1965-1966 (Box 10)
  - Civil Rights 1965-1966 (Box 10)
  - Classics (folder empty) 1965-1966 (Box 10)
  - Clinch Valley College - General 1965-1966 (Box 10)
  - Clinch Valley College - Building Program 1965-1966 (Box 10)
  - Clinch Valley College - Monthly Reports 1965-1966 (Box 10)
  - Clinch Valley College - Personnel 1965-1966 (Box 10)
  - College Entrance Examination Board (see Admissions) 1965-1966 (Box 10)
  - College of Arts and Sciences 1965-1966 (Box 10)
  - Colonnade Club 1965-1966 (Box 10)
  - Commerce - General 1965-1966 (Box 10)
  - Commerce - Personnel 1965-1966 (Box 10)
  - Computer Center 1965-1966 (Box 10)
  - Cooper, Weldon 1965-1966 (Box 10)
  - Copeley Hill (Married Student Housing) 1965-1966 (Box 10)
  - Council of Presidents Folder # 1 (see also Tax Study Commission) 1965-1966 (Box 10)
  - Council of Presidents Folder # 2 1965-1966 (Box 11)
  - Council of Southern Universities (see also Southern Fellowships Fund) 1965-1966 (Box 11)
  - "Da - Dm" Miscellaneous 1965-1966 (Box 11)
  - "Dn - Dz" Miscellaneous 1965-1966 (Box 11)
  - Darden, C. W., Jr. 1965-1966 (Box 12)
  - Darlington School - Board of Trustees 1965-1966 (Box 12)
  - Deans Luncheons 1965-1966 (Box 12)
  - Dean of the University (see Student Affairs) 1965-1966 (Box 12)
  - Degrees 1965-1966 (Box 12)
  - Ditchley Foundation 1965-1966 (Box 12)
  - Duncan, Andrew W. 1965-1966 (Box 12)
  - "E" Miscellaneous 1965-1966 (Box 12)
  - Economics 1965-1966 (Box 12)
  - Education - Compact for Education Planning Conference 1965-1966 (Box 12)
  - Education - General 1965-1966 (Box 12)
  - Education - Personnel 1965-1966 (Box 12)
  - Education - Rehabilitation Center (see Rehabilitation Center) 1965-1966 (Box 12)
  - Education - Educational Research, Division of 1965-1966 (Box 12)
  - Education Aid for State Employees 1965-1966 (Box 12)
  - Educational T. V. 1965-1966 (Box 13)
  - Emeriti 1965-1966 (Box 13)
  - Endowment Fund 1965-1966 (Box 13)
  - Engineering - General 1965-1966 (Box 13)
  - Engineering - Personnel 1965-1966 (Box 13)
  - English 1965-1966 (Box 13)
  - Enrollment (see also Registrar) 1965-1966 (Box 13)
  - "F" Miscellaneous 1965-1966 (Box 14)
  - Faculty - Five Year Faculty Staffing (folder empty) 1965-1966 (Box 14)
  - Faculty - General Faculty 1965-1966 (Box 14)
  - Faculty Orientation and Reception 1965-1966 (Box 14)
  - Faculty Tenure 1965-1966 (Box 14)
  - Faculty of Arts and Sciences - Academic Faculty 1965-1966 (Box 14)
  - Faculty of Arts and Sciences - Committees of 1965-1966 (Box 14)
  - Faculty of Arts and Sciences - Committee on Educational Policy and the Budget 1965-1966 (Box 14)
  - Faculty of Arts and Sciences - Department Chairmen (folder empty) 1965-1966 (Box 14)
  - Faculty of Arts and Sciences - General 1965-1966 (Box 14)
  - Faculty of Arts and Sciences - Personnel - "A" 1965-1966 (Box 14)
  - Faculty of Arts and Sciences - Personnel - "B" 1965-1966 (Box 14)
  - Faculty of Arts and Sciences - Personnel - "C" 1965-1966 (Box 14)
  - Faculty of Arts and Sciences - Personnel - "D" 1965-1966 (Box 14)
  - Faculty of Arts and Sciences - Personnel - "E" 1965-1966 (Box 14)
  - Faculty of Arts and Sciences - Personnel - "F" 1965-1966 (Box 14)
  - Faculty of Arts and Sciences - Personnel - "G" 1965-1966 (Box 14)
  - Faculty of Arts and Sciences - Personnel - "H" 1965-1966 (Box 15)
  - Faculty of Arts and Sciences - Personnel - "I" (folder empty) 1965-1966 (Box 15)
  - Faculty of Arts and Sciences - Personnel - "J" 1965-1966 (Box 15)
  - Faculty of Arts and Sciences - Personnel - "K" 1965-1966 (Box 15)
  - Faculty of Arts and Sciences - Personnel - "L" 1965-1966 (Box 15)
  - Faculty of Arts and Sciences - Personnel - "M" 1965-1966 (Box 15)
  - Faculty of Arts and Sciences - Personnel - "N" 1965-1966 (Box 15)
  - Faculty of Arts and Sciences - Personnel - "O" 1965-1966 (Box 15)
  - Faculty of Arts and Sciences - Personnel - "P" 1965-1966 (Box 15)
  - Faculty of Arts and Sciences - Personnel - "Q" 1965-1966 (Box 15)
  - Faculty of Arts and Sciences - Personnel - "R" 1965-1966 (Box 15)
  - Faculty of Arts and Sciences - Personnel - "S" 1965-1966 (Box 15)
  - Faculty of Arts and Sciences - Personnel - "T" 1965-1966 (Box 15)
  - Faculty of Arts and Sciences - Personnel - "U" 1965-1966 (Box 15)
  - Faculty of Arts and Sciences - Personnel - "V" 1965-1966 (Box 15)
  - Faculty of Arts and Sciences - Personnel - "W" 1965-1966 (Box 15)
  - Faculty of Arts and Sciences - Personnel - "X - Y - Z" 1965-1966 (Box 15)
  - Federal Legislation 1965-1966 (Box 15)
  - Federal Relations (folder empty) 1965-1966 (Box 15)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships 1965-1966 (Box 15)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships - Cross 1965-1966 (Box 15)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships - DuPont Regional 1965-1966 (Box 16)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships - Fulbright 1965-1966 (Box 16)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships - Love 1965-1966 (Box 16)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships - Rhodes 1965-1966 (Box 16)
  - Finals (see also Committee on Public Occasions) 1965-1966 (Box 16)
  - Financial Aid to Students 1965-1966 (Box 16)
  - Ford Foundation (see also 3 years Master's Program in Graduate Arts and Sciences and see also Madison, Adams, and Jefferson Papers) 1965-1966 (Box 16)
  - Foreign Student Advisor (see also Student Affairs) 1965-1966 (Box 16)
  - Founder's Day 1965-1966 (Box 17)
  - "G" Miscellaneous 1965-1966 (Box 17)
  - General Assembly (see also Legislative Program) 1965-1966 (Box 17)
  - General Studies 1965-1966 (Box 17)
  - General Studies - Branches proposed 1965-1966 (Box 17)
  - General Studies - Central Virginia Center 1965-1966 (Box 17)
  - General Studies - Eastern Shore Branch 1965-1966 (Box 17)
  - General Studies - Eastern Shore Branch - Personnel 1965-1966 (Box 18)
  - General Studies - Hampton Roads Center 1965-1966 (Box 18)
  - General Studies - Hampton Roads Center - Personnel 1965-1966 (Box 18)
  - General Studies - Lynchburg Branch 1965-1966 (Box 18)
  - General Studies - Lynchburg Branch - Personnel 1965-1966 (Box 18)
  - General Studies - Madison Center 1965-1966 (Box 18)
  - General Studies - Madison Center - Personnel 1965-1966 (Box 18)
  - General Studies - Northern Virginia Center 1965-1966 (Box 18)
  - General Studies - Northern Virginia Center - Personnel 1965-1966 (Box 18)
  - General Studies - Patrick Henry Branch 1965-1966 (Box 18)
  - General Studies - Patrick Henry Branch - Personnel 1965-1966 (Box 18)
  - General Studies - Richmond Center 1965-1966 (Box 18)
  - General Studies - Roanoke Center 1965-1966 (Box 18)
  - General Studies - Roanoke Center - Personnel 1965-1966 (Box 18)
  - General Studies - Southwest Virginia Center 1965-1966 (Box 18)
  - General Studies - Southwest Virginia Center - Personnel 1965-1966 (Box 18)
  - Geography (folder empty) 1965-1966 (Box 18)
  - Geology 1965-1966 (Box 18)
  - George Mason College - Folder # 1 1965-1966 (Box 18)
  - George Mason College - Folder # 2 1965-1966 (Box 19)
  - George Mason College - Monthly Reports 1965-1966 (Box 19)
  - George Mason College - Personnel 1965-1966 (Box 19)
  - George Mason College Foundation Incorporated 1965-1966 (Box 19)
  - Gilmer Hall 1965-1966 (Box 19)
  - Government and Foreign Affairs 1965-1966 (Box 19)
  - Governor's Office 1965-1966 (Box 19a)
  - Graduate Programs 1965-1966 (Box 19a)
  - Graduate School of Arts and Sciences 1965-1966 (Box 19a)
  - Graduate School of Arts and Sciences - 3-Years Master's Degree Program 1965-1966 (Box 19a)
  - Graduate School of Business Administration 1965-1966 (Box 19a)
  - Graduate Business - Personnel 1965-1966 (Box 19a)
  - Graduate Business - Sponsors 1965-1966 (Box 19a)
  - Graduate Degree Programs in Tidewater Virginia 1965-1966 (Box 19a)
  - Graphics, Department of 1965-1966 (Box 19a)
  - Guggenheim Foundation 1965-1966 (Box 19a)
  - "Ha - Hi" Miscellaneous 1965-1966 (Box 20)
  - "Hj - Hz" Miscellaneous 1965-1966 (Box 20)
  - Harvard Graduate Society Council 1965-1966 (Box 20)
  - Higher Education Act 1965-1966 (Box 20)
  - Higher Education Act - Title I 1965-1966 (Box 20)
  - Higher Education Act - Title II 1965-1966 (Box 21)
  - Higher Education Act - Title III 1965-1966 (Box 21)
  - Higher Education Act - Title IV 1965-1966 (Box 21)
  - Higher Education Act - Title V 1965-1966 (Box 21)
  - Higher Education Act - Title VI 1965-1966 (Box 21)
  - Higher Education Act Study Commission 1965-1966 (Box 21)
  - Highway Department 1965-1966 (Box 21)
  - History 1965-1966 (Box 21)
  - Honors Program 1965-1966 (Box 21)
  - Honor System and Honor Committee 1965-1966 (Box 21)
  - Housing 1965-1966 (Box 21)
  - "I" Miscellaneous 1965-1966 (Box 21)
  - Information Services (see Public Relations and Development) 1965-1966 (Box 22)
  - Institute of Current World Affairs 1965-1966 (Box 22)
  - Institute of Early American History and Culture 1965-1966 (Box 22)
  - Institute of Government 1965-1966 (Box 22)
  - Institute of International Education 1965-1966 (Box 22)
  - Institutional Analysis, Office of 1965-1966 (Box 22)
  - Institutional Self-Study 1965-1966 (Box 23)
  - Inventions and Patents (folder empty) 1965-1966 (Box 23)
  - Invitations - "A" 1965-1966 (Box 23)
  - Invitations - "B" 1965-1966 (Box 23)
  - Invitations - "C" 1965-1966 (Box 23)
  - Invitations - "D" 1965-1966 (Box 23)
  - Invitations - "E" 1965-1966 (Box 23)
  - Invitations - "F" 1965-1966 (Box 23)
  - Invitations - "G" 1965-1966 (Box 23)
  - Invitations - "H" 1965-1966 (Box 23)
  - Invitations - "I" 1965-1966 (Box 23)
  - Invitations - "J" 1965-1966 (Box 24)
  - Invitations - "K" 1965-1966 (Box 24)
  - Invitations - "L" 1965-1966 (Box 24)
  - Invitations - "M" 1965-1966 (Box 24)
  - Invitations - "N" 1965-1966 (Box 24)
  - Invitations - "O" 1965-1966 (Box 24)
  - Invitations - "P" 1965-1966 (Box 24)
  - Invitations - "Q" (folder empty) 1965-1966 (Box 24)
  - Invitations - "R" 1965-1966 (Box 24)
  - Invitations - "S" 1965-1966 (Box 24)
  - Invitations - "T" 1965-1966 (Box 24)
  - Invitations - "U" 1965-1966 (Box 25)
  - Invitations - "V" 1965-1966 (Box 25)
  - Invitations - "W" 1965-1966 (Box 25)
  - Invitations - "X - Y - Z" 1965-1966 (Box 25)
  - "J" Miscellaneous 1965-1966 (Box 25)
  - Thomas Jefferson Award 1965-1966 (Box 25)
  - Thomas Jefferson Center 1965-1966 (Box 25)
  - Thomas Jefferson Memorial Foundation (see also Founder's Day) 1965-1966 (Box 25)
  - Thomas Jefferson Memorial Foundation 1965-1966 (Box 25)
  - Thomas Jefferson Memorial Foundation - Minutes 1965-1966 (Box 25)
  - Jefferson Society 1965-1966 (Box 25)
  - "L" Miscellaneous 1965-1966 (Box 26)
  - Law - General 1965-1966 (Box 26)
  - Law - Personnel 1965-1966 (Box 26)
  - Lectures (Folder Empty) 1965-1966 (Box 26)
  - Legal 1965-1966 (Box 27)
  - Legal - Estates, Eddes 1965-1966 (Box 27)
  - Legislative Program 1965-1966 (Box 27)
  - Liberal Arts 1965-1966 (Box 27)
  - Library 1965-1966 (Box 27)
  - Library - Board of Alderman 1965-1966 (Box 27)
  - Life Sciences Building (folder empty) 1965-1966 (Box 27)
  - Longwood Foundation (folder empty) 1965-1966 (Box 27)
  - "Mc" Miscellaneous 1965-1966 (Box 27)
  - McConnell Award (see Thomas Jefferson Award) 1965-1966 (Box 27)
  - "Ma - Me" Miscellaneous 1965-1966 (Box 28)
  - "Mi - Mz" Miscellaneous 1965-1966 (Box 28)
  - Mace (folder empty) 1965-1966 (Box 28)
  - Madison Papers (see also Adams and Jefferson Papers) 1965-1966 (Box 28)
  - Marine Science 1965-1966 (Box 28)
  - Markle Foundation 1965-1966 (Box 28)
  - Mary Washington College 1965-1966 (Box 29)
  - Mary Washington College - Building Program 1965-1966 (Box 29)
  - Mary Washington College - Financial 1965-1966 (Box 29)
  - Mary Washington College - Personnel 1965-1966 (Box 29)
  - Master Site Plan 1965-1966 (Box 29)
  - Mathematics 1965-1966 (Box 29)
  - Medical Center 1965-1966 (Box 29)
  - Medical Center - Hospital 1965-1966 (Box 30)
  - Medical Center - Hospital - Monthly Statistical Reports 1965-1966 (Box 30)
  - Medical Center - Nursing 1965-1966 (Box 30)
  - Medical Center - Nursing - Personnel 1965-1966 (Box 30)
  - Medical Center - Rehabilitation and Training Center 1965-1966 (Box 30)
  - Medical Center - Hospital - Rehabilitation and Training Center (see Rehabilitation Center) (folder empty) 1965-1966 (Box 30)
  - Medical Center - Hospital - Operating Budgets and Reports 1965-1966 (Box 30)
  - Medical Center - Reports on Current Operations 1965-1966 (Box 30)
  - Medical Center - Medical School 1965-1966 (Box 31)
  - Medical Center - Personnel "A - G" 1965-1966 (Box 31)
  - Medical Center - Personnel "H - Z" 1965-1966 (Box 31)
  - Mental Health 1965-1966 (Box 31)
  - Modern Languages 1965-1966 (Box 31)
  - Monroe Foundation and Library 1965-1966 (Box 31)
  - Monroe Papers (folder empty) 1965-1966 (Box 31)
  - Music 1965-1966 (Box 31)
  - "N" Miscellaneous 1965-1966 (Box 32)
  - National Aeronautics and Space Administration (see also VARC: Research and Training Funds Policy) 1965-1966 (Box 32)
  - National Association of State Universities and Land-Grant Colleges - # 1 1965-1966 (Box 32)
  - National Association of State Universities and Land-Grant Colleges - # 2 1965-1966 (Box 33)
  - National Association of State Universities and Land-Grant Colleges - # 3 1965-1966 (Box 33)
  - National Association of State Universities and Land-Grant Colleges - International Letters 1965-1966 (Box 34)
  - National Association of State Universities and Land-Grant Colleges - Circular Letters 1965-1966 (Box 34)
  - National Commission on Accrediting 1965-1966 (Box 34)
  - National Defense Education Act (or National Defense Student Loan) 1965-1966 (Box 35)
  - National Historical Publications Commission (see also Madison and Adams Papers) 1965-1966 (Box 35)
  - National Science Foundation - 1964-1965 1965-1966 (Box 35)
  - National Science Foundation - 1965-1966 1965-1966 (Box 35)
  - National Science Foundation - Institutional Grant for Science 1965-1966 (Box 35)
  - Navy ROTC 1965-1966 (Box 35)
  - Newcomb Hall (see also Committee on University Union) 1965-1966 (Box 36)
  - Newcomen Society 1965-1966 (Box 36)
  - News Letter 1965-1966 (Box 36)
  - Newspaper Clippings 1965-1966 (Box 36)
  - North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO Visiting Professors Program) 1965-1966 (Box 36)
  - Nursing (see Medical Center) 1965-1966 (Box 36)
  - "O" Miscellaneous 1965-1966 (Box 36)
  - Office - General Stores 1965-1966 (Box 36)
  - Office - Invoices, July - December, 1965 1965-1966 (Box 36)
  - Office - Invoices, January - June 1966 1965-1966 (Box 36)
  - Office - Information 1965-1966 (Box 37)
  - Office - Supplies 1965-1966 (Box 37)
  - Office - Travel 1965-1966 (Box 37)
  - Office of institutional Research 1965-1966 (Box 37)
  - "P - Ph" Miscellaneous 1965-1966 (Box 37)
  - "Pi - Pz" Miscellaneous 1965-1966 (Box 37)
  - Personnel (Richmond and Local Offices) 1965-1966 (Box 38)
  - Phi Beta Kappa 1965-1966 (Box 38)
  - Philosophy 1965-1966 (Box 38)
  - Photographs 1965-1966 (Box 38)
  - Physics 1965-1966 (Box 38)
  - Planning Department (see also individual building programs) 1965-1966 (Box 38)
  - Project Status Reports 1965-1966 (Box 38)
  - Provost of the University 1965-1966 (Box 38)
  - Psychology 1965-1966 (Box 38)
  - Publications 1965-1966 (Box 38)
  - Public Relations 1965-1966 (Box 38)
  - Purchasing (Richmond and University) 1965-1966 (Box 38)
  - "Q" Miscellaneous 1965-1966 (Box 38)
  - Questionnaires and Inquiries (folder empty) 1965-1966 (Box 38)
  - "R" Miscellaneous 1965-1966 (Box 38)
  - Radiation Protection 1965-1966 (Box 38)
  - Radio 1965-1966 (Box 39)
  - Raven Society 1965-1966 (Box 39)
  - Recommendations 1965-1966 (Box 39)
  - Regional Education Laboratory - Central Atlantic 1965-1966 (Box 39)
  - Regional Education Laboratory - Mid-South 1965-1966 (Box 39)
  - Registrar 1965-1966 (Box 39)
  - Registrar - Student Reports 1965-1966 (Box 39)
  - Rehabilitation Center 1965-1966 (Box 39)
  - Religion 1965-1966 (Box 39)
  - Research 1965-1966 (Box 39)
  - "S - Sl" Miscellaneous 1965-1966 (Box 39)
  - "Sm - So" Miscellaneous 1965-1966 (Box 39)
  - "Sp - Sz" Miscellaneous 1965-1966 (Box 40)
  - Salaries (see also Personnel) 1965-1966 (Box 40)
  - Scholarships (see Fellowships and Scholarships) 1965-1966 (Box 40)
  - Scholars-in-Residence 1965-1966 (Box 40)
  - Security, Department of 1965-1966 (Box 40)
  - Senate, University 1965-1966 (Box 40)
  - Senior Scholars Research 1965-1966 (Box 40)
  - Seven Society 1965-1966 (Box 40)
  - Shannon - Tokyo Trip 1965-1966 (Box 40)
  - Southern Association of Land-Grant Colleges 1965-1966 (Box 40)
  - Southern Association of Colleges and Schools 1965-1966 (Box 41)
  - Southern Regional Education Board 1965-1966 (Box 41)
  - Southern University Conference 1965-1966 (Box 41)
  - Space Utilization 1965-1966 (Box 41)
  - Speeches 1965-1966 (Box 41)
  - Speech - Southwestern at Memphis, 2 May 1966 1965-1966 (Box 41)
  - Speech - O. D. K., 21 April 1966 1965-1966 (Box 41)
  - Speech - Association of Virginia Colleges, 20 February 1965 1965-1966 (Box 41)
  - Speech - Summer School Graduation, 14 August 1965 1965-1966 (Box 42)
  - Speech - "Continuity and Change" - School of Consumer Banking, 20 August 1965 1965-1966 (Box 42)
  - Speech - "The Supremacy of Ideas" - Convocation, Madison College, 23 September 1965 1965-1966 (Box 42)
  - Speech - Convocation Talk to First-Year Men, 13 September 1965 1965-1966 (Box 42)
  - Speech - 10 November 1965 (folder empty) 1965-1966 (Box 42)